Codex can move from a request to implementation in
seconds, while important assumptions remain hidden.
PromptTripwire makes compatibility, dependency,
permission, and external-effect decisions visible before
execution begins.
PromptTripwire is a local-first safety layer for Codex.
Version zero point one point two installs the runtime
and Plugin together.
In a new task, the user explicitly invokes prompt-tripwire
preflight.
There is no automatic hook, hosted backend, or separate
API key.
It uses the Codex CLI and App Server login
already on this Mac.
The Skill sends the full task and exact repository
snapshot to three independent, read-only Codex App Server
planning threads powered by GPT-5.
6-sol.
A separate GPT-5.
6-terra comparator reads only their structured plans,
without tools.
Deterministic policy converts disagreements and disclosed
consequences into explicit decisions.
The source checkout remains unchanged.
This is a real version zero point one point
two Decision Inbox from a live inspect run.
The safe fixture surfaces one compatibility decision and
no dependency blocker.
It remains untouched and unapproved.
PromptTripwire shows evidence and choices, but never
chooses or approves for the user.
The Inbox capture remains untouched and unapproved.
The next scenes use a separate completed safe-fixture run
that was manually approved earlier.
That earlier approval compiled choices into a contract
bound to the exact task and repository snapshot.
It declares allowed paths, checks, and prohibited effects.
Network, deploy, release, remote writes, secrets,
destructive operations, and permission expansion remain
denied by the P0 executor.
Human review can authorize only disclosed local code
preparation, not those effects.
Stale or unapproved contracts cannot run.
Approved implementation starts in PromptTripwire's
isolated Codex thread and disposable Git worktree, never
in the caller's checkout.
The controller checks structured App Server actions
against the contract.
In this completed safe-fixture run, Codex changed only the
greeting module and test, then passed npm test.
No network, permission expansion, or external effect was
observed.
The worktree was removed after evidence collection.
The report links the run, contract, snapshot, models,
observed actions, changed paths, checks, deviations, and
remaining unknowns.
Both changed paths stayed inside the approved contract and
the required test passed.
The original Codex task receives this compact summary, not
raw reasoning, secrets, or long logs.
The Codex Plugin stays thin.
Its Skill invokes the same CLI, policy, contract compiler,
containment, and report engine used everywhere else.
A deterministic re-entry flag prevents the isolated child
Codex from invoking PromptTripwire again.
Version zero point one point two targets macOS on
Apple silicon, Node twenty-four point fifteen or newer,
and Codex CLI zero point one forty-four point four.
PromptTripwire shows where Codex plans disagree before
code is written, while approval stays in human hands.
Inspect first.
Decide explicitly.
Execute inside the contract.
Review the evidence.